[
    {
        "subject":"Data Structure & Algorithm",
        "question":" How can we describe an array in the best possible way?",
        "option1":"The Array shows a hierarchical structure.",
        "option2":"Arrays are immutable.",
        "option3":"Container that stores the elements of similar types",
        "option4":"The Array is not a data structure",
        "answer":"Container that stores the elements of similar types"   
     },
     {
        "subject":"Data Structure & Algorithm",
        "question":"Which of the following is the correct way of declaring an array?",
        "option1":"int javatpoint;",
        "option2":"javatpoint;",
        "option3":"javatpoint{20};",
        "option4":"array javatpoint[10];",
        "answer":"int javatpoint[10];"   
     },{
        "subject":"Data Structure & Algorithm",
        "question":"How can we initialize an array in C language?",
        "option1":"int arr[2]=(10, 20)",
        "option2":"int arr(2)={10, 20}",
        "option3":"int arr[2] = {10, 20}",
        "option4":"int arr(2) = (10, 20)",
        "answer":"int arr[2] = {10, 20}"   
     },{
        "subject":"Data Structure & Algorithm",
        "question":"Which of the following is the advantage of the array data structure?",
        "option1":"Elements of mixed data types can be stored.",
        "option2":"Easier to access the elements in an array",
        "option3":"Index of the first element starts from 1.",
        "option4":"Elements of an array cannot be sorted",
        "answer":"Easier to access the elements in an array"   
     },{
        "subject":"Data Structure & Algorithm",
        "question":"Which of the following highly uses the concept of an array?",
        "option1":"Binary Search tree",
        "option2":"Caching",
        "option3":"Spatial locality",
        "option4":"Scheduling of Processes",
        "answer":"Spatial locality"   
     },{
        "subject":"Data Structure & Algorithm",
        "question":"Which of the following is the disadvantage of the array?",
        "option1":"Stack and Queue data structures can be implemented through an array.",
        "option2":"Index of the first element in an array can be negative",
        "option3":"Wastage of memory if the elements inserted in an array are lesser than the allocated size",
        "option4":"Elements can be accessed sequentially.",
        "answer":"Wastage of memory if the elements inserted in an array are lesser than the allocated size"   
     },{
        "subject":"Data Structure & Algorithm",
        "question":"Which one of the following is the size of int arr[9] assuming that int is of 4 bytes?",
        "option1":"9",
        "option2":"36",
        "option3":"35",
        "option4":"None of the above",
        "answer":"36"   
     },{
        "subject":"Data Structure & Algorithm",
        "question":"Which one of the following is the process of inserting an element in the stack?",
        "option1":"Insert",
        "option2":"Add",
        "option3":"Push",
        "option4":"None of the above",
        "answer":"Push"   
     },{
        "subject":"Data Structure & Algorithm",
        "question":"When the user tries to delete the element from the empty stack then the condition is said to be a ____",
        "option1":"Underflow",
        "option2":"Garbage collection",
        "option3":"Overflow",
        "option4":"None of the above",
        "answer":"Underflow"   
     },{
        "subject":"Data Structure & Algorithm",
        "question":"If the size of the stack is 10 and we try to add the 11th element in the stack then the condition is known as___",
        "option1":"Underflow",
        "option2":"Garbage collection",
        "option3":"Overflow",
        "option4":"None of the above",
        "answer":"Overflow"   
     },{
        "subject":"Data Structure & Algorithm",
        "question":"Which one of the following is not the application of the stack data structure",
        "option1":"String reversal",
        "option2":"Recursion",
        "option3":"Backtracking",
        "option4":"Asynchronous data transfer",
        "answer":"Asynchronous data transfer"   
     },{
        "subject":"Data Structure & Algorithm",
        "question":"Which data structure is mainly used for implementing the recursive algorithm?",
        "option1":"Queue",
        "option2":"Stack",
        "option3":"Binary tree",
        "option4":"Linked list",
        "answer":"Stack"   
     },{
        "subject":"Data Structure & Algorithm",
        "question":" Which data structure is required to convert the infix to prefix notation?",
        "option1":"Stack",
        "option2":"Linked list",
        "option3":"Binary tree",
        "option4":"Queue",
        "answer":"Stack"   
     },{
        "subject":"Data Structure & Algorithm",
        "question":"Which of the following is the infix expression?",
        "option1":"A+B*C",
        "option2":"+A*BC",
        "option3":"ABC+*",
        "option4":"None of the above",
        "answer":"A+B*C"   
     }
]